(ヤマト)サクラを 傷つけたのは…➡
You're the one...
who hurt Sakura, Naruto.
キミだよ… ナルト。
(サクラ)ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
((自来也 : ナルト…。
Naruto...
ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
お前…➡
you...
(何も… 覚えてないのか？))
don't... remember anything...?
(ナルト)じゃあ… あの橋も…➡
Then... that bridge...
and that crater...
あの えぐれた地面も…。
そう… キミが やった…。
Yes, you did it...
サクラちゃんの… ケガも…？
And Sakura-chan's wound as well...!
そうだ…。
That's right!
(ヤマト)サクラは キミを傷つけまいと➡
Sakura didn't want
to hurt you...
キミに ウソをついた。
so she lied to you.
サクラに ケガをさせた件については➡
I'm also responsible
for Sakura getting injured.
ボクにも 責任がある。
こういうときのために ボクが➡
And here I was assigned
to Team Kakashi...
カカシ班に 配属されたってのにね…。
for a time like this...
キミの あの 九尾の力…➡
I have special powers...
ボクは 人柱力の力を
抑えることが できる➡
with which I can control
your Nine-Tails power.
特別な力を もってる。
(ヤマト)だから キミは
あまり 心配しなくてもいい。
So you don't really
need to worry.
少なくとも…
ボクが キミのそばにいる間だけは…。
At least...
while I'm by your side.
つまり 今は… わざわざ キミに➡
In other words, I didn't have
to go to the trouble
of telling you the truth
at this point...
本当のことを 言わなくても
よかった…。
けど なぜ 話したか…。
But why did I tell you?
確かに… あの力を使えば➡
There's no doubt that
using that power
might be a quick way for you
to save Sasuke.
サスケを助ける
近道になるかもしれない。
だが あの九尾に頼った強さは➡
But strength gained
from relying on the Nine-Tails...
本当のキミの 力じゃない。
is not your true power.
これからも
この 九尾の力に頼れば➡
You'll end up tormenting yourself
if you rely on the power...
自分自身を
苦しめることになるし➡
of the Nine-Tails from here on.
仲間を 傷つけてしまう力にも
なりえる。
And it could turn into a power
that hurts your friends.
今回のようにね…。
Like what happened this time.
(ヤマト)キミも 薄々…
気づいていたはず。
You should already have
vaguely picked up on it.
でも 力の解放を
止めようとしなかったのは➡
But you didn't attempt to stop
the release of the power...
焦っていたからだろう？
That's because
you were impatient, right?
今から キミの 九尾の力は
ボクが 完全に抑える。
I will now completely suppress
your Nine-Tails power.
だが それで
キミが 弱くなったと思ったら➡
But you're sorely mistaken...
if you think that will
make you weaker.
大間違いだよ。
そんな力に 頼らなくても
キミは 十分 強いはずなんだよ。
You should be
sufficiently powerful...
without having to rely
on that Chakra.
キミは 勘違いしてないか？
I think you've got
the wrong idea about this.
キミの強さの源は
九尾の チャクラではなく➡
The source of your strength
isn't the Nine-Tails Chakra.
恐るべき 九尾のチャクラに耐えうる➡
It's the power of
your own Chakra...
その キミ自身の チャクラの力だ。
that can withstand the formidable
Nine-Tails Chakra.
サスケを 助けたいなら…➡
If you want to save Sasuke,
do it with your own power.
キミ自身の力で 助け出せ。
(ヤマト)サスケの姿を 見たいなら➡
If you want to see Sasuke...
do it with your own eyes,
not the Nine-Tails'.
九尾の目ではなく 自分の目で…。
(ヤマト)そして
サクラを 守りたいなら…➡
And if you want
to protect Sakura...
九尾の力ではなく 自分の力で！
do it with your own power,
not the Nine-Tails'!
うん！
Right!
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forgotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenain deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
EVERDAY hereafter is a shining day.
everyday kono saki mo shining day
Unchanging singin', a bright morning smile.
kawarazu singin' hikaru asa no smile
This is the last farewell on funny days.
kore de miosame no funny days
Leaping into the future I see. Go far, dream of my heart.
tobidatsu future mezashita go far kokoro no dream of
I'll go the distance, the endless sky is blue.
i'll go the distance mihatenu sora wa blue
I've hitched a ride on the star ship, this is the best forever trip.
norikonda star ship kore ga saigo no forever trip
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenai deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah, it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
Thank you my friend.
thank you my friend
Ah even now,
aa ano hi no koto
I still remember that day.
ima demo mada oboeteru kara
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah those days that will never come back.
aa mou nidoto sou modoranai days
Woah I'll go the distance!
woah i'll go the distance
The Unfinished Page
(大蛇丸)カブト…。
Kabuto... Take care of that
after we get back.
そういうのは
帰ってからにしなさい。
いえね… なるべく
すぐに おとしておかないと➡
No, you see...
if I don't wash these off
as soon as possible,
切れ味が あっという間に
おちてしまうんですよ。
the cutting quality will deteriorate
just like that...
(大蛇丸)フン…。
《大丈夫… 痛みは減ってきた》
It's okay...
The pain's starting to go away.
《隊長とナルト… まだかしら？
そうだ…》
Are Naruto and the captain
still at it?
Oh yeah...
《そういえば さっきの…》
Come to think of it,
the thing I picked up earlier...
《ない…》
It's gone...
Here it is...
《あった…》
((サイ : 先に行っててください。
ボクも片したら すぐに行きます。
Please go on ahead.
I'll catch up once
I've tidied up.
手伝うわ。
I'll help.
(サクラ)これ 印刷じゃないわね？
This... isn't printed.
これも あなたが描いたの？
(サイ)あぁ。
Did you draw this, too?
Yes.
へぇ～ 絵本かぁ。
Wow, it's a picture book, huh?
それ 行く途中に
見せてもらってもいい？
Can I take a look at it
along the way?
それは ダメだよ。
これ まだ 完成してないから。
I can't let you see it.
It's not finished yet...
それに 人には
渡さないことにしてるんだ。
And I don't hand this over
to people.
This is my brother's book, so...
(サイ)これは 兄さんのだからね))
《…やはり ない》
Just as I thought, it's gone...
((その話 何を根拠に
信じればいいの？))
How can I...
be sure that's true?
《あのときか…》
I lost it back then, huh...?
Is something the matter, Sai?
どうかしたの？ サイとやら…。
いえ… なんでも…。
No... It's nothing...
…そう。
I see...
(カブト)それより 大蛇丸様…。
ん？
More importantly,
Orochimaru-sama...
(カブト)帰ったら 無傷の男の死体を
早急に 一ついただけますか？
When we get back,
can you give me...
an intact male corpse
as quickly as possible?
まだ ストックは 持ってるでしょ？
ええ…。
Don't you still have
bodies in stock?
Yes, I do...
ただ 15～16歳の男のストックは➡
But I'm out of
the fifteen to sixteen-year-old...
さっきので
無くなりましたから…。
We lost one in
the incident earlier, so...
巻物の中は 常に年齢順に
きちんと保存しておかないと➡
It doesn't feel right...
unless they are always stored properly
in order of age inside the scroll.
落ち着かなくて…。
Kabuto...
Are you type-A blood?
カブト… あなた Ａ型だったかしら？
いえ… ＡＢ型ですけど。
No... I'm AB...
そう… 意外ね。
(カブト)そうでもないですよ。
I see...
That's surprising...
Not really.
(カブト)では そろそろ
行きましょうか。
Okay, shall we get going
pretty soon...?
アジトまで もう少しですからね。
フン…。
We have a little further to go
before reaching the hideout.
(ヤマト)まずは この図を見てくれ。
First, take a look
at this diagram.
これは 敵を追い込むための
陣形の一つを 図にしたものだ。
This is a diagram of a formation
for cornering an enemy.
実際の任務においては
敵の数 味方の人員によって➡
In actual missions,
various scenarios can develop...
いろんなケースが
生まれてくるんだが➡
depending on the number
of enemies and number of allies.
まずは…。
First off...
何なの？
What's the deal...
この本…。
with this book...?
それから この場合だけど…。
And then...
in a scenario like this...
おい ちゃんと聞いて…。
(サクラ)ちょっと ２人とも来てみて。
Hey, are you liste--
Both of you,
come here a minute!
(サクラ)早く！
Hurry!
どうかしたのか？ サクラちゃん。
Is something wrong,
Sakura-chan?
これを見て。
Look at this.
Oh! That's Sai's...
それってば サイの…。
(ヤマト)さっき拾った
サイが描いたっていう絵本だね。
That's the picture book
we picked up that Sai drew, huh?
どんな内容なんだい？
What's in it?
それがわかれば サイのことが
少しは わかるかもしれない。
If we figure that out,
we might be able
to find out a little about Sai...
えぇ… そう思って
私も読んでみたんだけど…。
Right. That's what I was thinking,
so I tried reading it, but...
What kind of a story is it?
どんなストーリーなんだってばよ？
それが… よくわからなくて…。
Actually... I don't really know...
なんで？
どういうことだ？
Why?
What do you mean?
(サクラ)セリフや文字は 一切なし…。
There are no words
or dialogue at all...
ホントだ…。
You're right...
なんか… 本の表紙と
裏表紙に描かれてる➡
It kind of...
looks like a story about the two boys
on the front and back cover...
２人の少年の物語みたい…。
で 本の両扉から
真ん中のページに向かって➡
And... it's got the story
of the two boys...
starting from both title pages
of the book...
２人の少年の物語が
スタートする構成になってる。
and progressing to the middle...
When you look at the book starting with
this boy with black hair...
この黒髪の少年のほうから
見ていくと➡
次のページは…。
the next page...
常に右ページは同じ少年で➡
always has the same boy
on the right page...
左ページは ページごとに
違う人が描かれてる。
And there's a different person
drawn on each left page...
ほらね。
See...?
Huh...?!
あれ… これ 戻してみて。
This is... Go back!
やっぱり… この 子供のほう。
I knew it...
This kid... looks a little different
when you go to the next page.
次のページになると
少し 格好が変わってる。
You're right...
(サクラ)ホントだ…。
でもって ほら… 前のページの
左に描かれてるヤツの武器と➡
And look...
He has the same weapon as
the guy drawn on the previous page...
同じのを持ってる。
Hmm, it looks like it's a story
where the boy defeats enemies...
どうやら 少年が
敵を倒していくお話みたいだね。
これ… 戦ったら
敵の武器や鎧を➡
Look at this...
After fighting,
he takes the enemy's weapon
and armor...
奪い取っていってるんだ…。
やっぱり… 次も その次も！
Just as I thought...
The next page...
and the next page, too...
Oh, come to think of it!
そういえば…。
やっぱり… 配置は逆だけど➡
I knew it...
The positioning is reversed...
この白い髪の少年も
同じようになってる。
but this boy with the white hair
is the same, too.
敵と戦って 少年たちが
成長していくお話か…。
So it's a story where these boys
grow by battling enemies, huh...?
ちょっと待つってばよ。
Just a minute...
If they're defeating enemies
from both sides...
両方から
敵を倒してくってことは➡
最後は… どうなるんだ？
then what happens at the end?!
That's the problem.
問題は… そこなのよ。
見て。
Look...
What's up with... this picture?
なんだってばよ… この絵。
This is a strange picture.
変な絵…。
この絵本➡
In this picture book...
真ん中の見開きのページだけ
描きかけなの。
only the facing pages
in the middle are incomplete...
これ… なんか
気味悪いってばよ。
This is... kind of creepy...
完成してないとは言ってたけど➡
He said it wasn't finished...
なぜ顔を描いてないんだろう？
But why isn't there a face
drawn in...?
Doesn't... the guy with
the black hair...
なぁ なんかさ…
黒髪のヤツのほう➡
サイに似てねえか？
kind of look like Sai?
You're right.
(サクラ)そうね…。
(ヤマト)自分を描いていたのか。
Did he draw himself...?
(サクラ)じゃあ この
白い髪の少年は 誰なんだろう？
Then who is this boy...
with the white hair?
((これ… まだ完成してないから。
I can't let you see it.
It's not finished yet.
それに 人には
渡さないことにしてるんだ。
And I don't hand this over
to people.
(これは 兄さんのだからね))
This is my older brother's book, so...
もしかして サイのお兄さん？
Could it be...
It's Sai's... Older Brother...?
えっ？
((あなたも兄弟がいるなら➡
If you have a brother,
you should be able to imagine
その兄弟が
いなくなったときのこと➡
what it would be like
to lose him, right?
少しは 想像できるでしょ！
ん？ あぁ… うん まぁね。
Yeah, well... you could say that...
(兄さん もう死んでるし…))
My brother's dead, after all.
じゃあ これ…。
Then this...
中央の見開きって
サイと お兄さんが？
These facing pages
in the center...
It's Sai... and his older brother...
いくわよ。
はい。
Let's go.
Yes, sir.
《あそこか…》
Over there, huh...?
サイの兄ちゃん… まさか!?
Sai's older brother...
Don't tell me!
Could it be...?!
《もしや…》
どうやら 分身のボクが
アジトを突き止めたようだ。
It appears my clone
has located the hideout.
そろそろ いこう！
Let's get going.
《あれは…》
That's...
You're late...
(サスケ)遅かったな…。
The clouds
drift accross
a distant sky,
The clouds
drift accross
a distant sky,
sora wa haruka
kumo wa nagarete
Far, far, far away,
beyond the horizon.
tooku tooku tooku
ni kogaretemo
Where will I go
from here and
what do I want?
Where will I go
from here and
what do I want?
doko o mezashite boku
wa fumidasu no ka
It's time to break
through my
fears and doubts.
It's time to break
through my
fears and doubts.
mayoi o ima
furikitte
Even though
I have a destiny
that I can't
escape from,
Even though
I have a destiny
that I can't
escape from,
nigeba no nai
unmei demo
I'm searching
for tomorrow.
asu o sagashite
Because the bonds
of friendship
keep me strong.
Because the bonds
of friendship
keep me strong.
boku o tsuyoku
suru no wa
nakama no kizuna
boku o tsuyoku
suru no wa
nakama no kizuna
Awaken the wild
side and let loose
the feelings!
Awaken the wild
side and let loose
the feelings!
mezamero yasei
afuredashita
kanjou
mezamero yasei
afuredashita
kanjou
Hidden within
my heart as I
smile recklessly.
Hidden within
my heart as I
smile recklessly.
mune ni himete
gamushara
no egao de
mune ni himete
gamushara
no egao de
And it's only when
I shout that the
truth is echoed.
And it's only when
I shout that the
truth is echoed.
sakebigoe wa
woah woah
shinjitsu dake
hibiku darou
sakebigoe wa
woah woah
shinjitsu dake
hibiku darou
My heart burns
and I'll hold on
to your hand.
My heart burns
and I'll hold on
to your hand.
kokoro moyase
soshite te o
tsunagou
kokoro moyase
soshite te o
tsunagou
If we're gonna
pursue those
eternal desires.
If we're gonna
pursue those
eternal desires.
yume ni
kometa eien
no negai o
yume ni
kometa eien
no negai o
Your prayer will
be granted,
motomeru nara
woah woah
今回から ２回にわたって➡
Because the light
you seek lies there.
sagashiteru
hikari wa kitto
soko ni aru sa
sagashiteru
hikari wa kitto
soko ni aru sa
サスケ君のことを振り返るわ。
(サクラ)サスケ君は アカデミーを
首席で卒業した クールな天才！
彼の野望は一族を滅ぼした兄
イタチに復讐すること。
Awaken the
beast within!
mezamero
yasei
Hmph,
It's you...
At last,
they meet again.
Finally.
そんなサスケ君に
いちいち からんでいったのが➡
Next Episode
万年おちこぼれのナルトだった。
What's this feeling?
What's this chill and sweat?
((この うすらとんかち！
なんだ？ お前！
I'm not supposed to have
any emotions.
(せっかく 助けにきてやったのに))
(サクラ)はじめは サスケ君に
全然 敵わなかったナルトだけど…。
Don't tell me that just by looking
into his eyes for an instant
I feared him within the depths of
my soul that even I can't perceive?!
((ケガはねえかよ ビビリ君))
(サクラ)持ち前の根性と意外性で
めきめき強くなっていったっけ。
Is he Uchiha Sasuke,
the man Naruto-kun has continued
to search for all this time?!
((ケガはねえかよ… ビビリ君))
Infiltration! The Den of the Snake
Next time: "Infiltration: The Den of the Snake"
(サクラ)そして ついに…。
((オレは お前とも戦いたい))
Notable People in the Leaf Village.
このとき ２人は
本当のライバルになったのね！
We will now take a look back
at Sasuke-kun in two parts.
それでは 続きは
次回の短冊帖で！
Sasuke-kun is a calm and collected genius
who graduated at the top of
his class in the Academy.
His ambition is to get revenge
against his older brother, Itachi,
who brought his clan to ruin.
Naruto, the hopeless failure,
always got into fights with Sasuke-kun.
You idiot!
What's with you?!
And here I went to the trouble
of coming to save you!
At first, Naruto was no match
for Sasuke-kun at all...
You're not hurt, are you, scaredy-cat?
But Naruto got remarkably strong
with his inherent determination
and unpredictability.
You're not hurt are you, scaredy-cat?
And then at last...
I want to fight you...
At that moment, the two of them
finally became true rivals.
We'll continue this next time.